RG 004:039, Eastford Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Eastford Probate Court records
1849-1912
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Eastford District)
2.5 cubic feet
Record books, none; Probate files, 1849-1912.
RG004_039
1914-004
Historical Note
Eastford, Windham County, Town established in May 1847, Parent Town: Ashford
The Eastford Probate District was constituted June 21, 1849, from the Ashford Probate District. The Town of Eastford section of the Eastford Probate District merged on January 5, 2011 with the Ashford, Brooklyn, Pomfret, Putnam, Thompson, and Woodstock Probate Districts to create the Northeast Probate District. The Northeast Probate District serves the municipalities of Ashford, Brooklyn, Eastford, Pomfret, Putnam, Thompson, and Woodstock.
Town of Eastford, Probate District chronology:
May 1847 - June 20, 1849, Ashford District
June 21, 1849 - January 4, 2011, Eastford District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Northeast District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, None. Contact the probate court to access original record books. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1849-1912. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Inventory control book, 1849-1912 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Probate files are arranged alphabetically in one series.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. Note: CSL does not hold any original record books. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1914-004 are represented in this index.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Eastford
Places:
Eastford (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 1-4, 6-8, 1849-1923 (volume 5 was missing at the time of filming October 1983); probate files, 1849-1912; and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1914-004 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): July 1, 1914 (1849-1912).
Container List
- Probate files, 1849-1912; 2.5 cubic feet; 1914-004
  - Adams - Bowen, B., 1849-1912 (Drawer 1)
  - Bowen, C. - Clark, 1849-1912 (Drawer 2)
  - Cole - Gurley, 1849-1912 (Drawer 3)
  - Hall - Lyon, E., 1849-1912 (Drawer 4)
  - Lyon, G. - Potter, 1849-1912 (Drawer 5)
  - Preston - Snow, 1849-1912 (Drawer 6)
  - Spaulding - Walker, P., 1849-1912 (Drawer 7)
  - Walker, Q - Z.; Miscellaneous, 1849-1912 (Drawer 8)
- Inventory Control Book, 1849-1912; T003073
  Index of probate files in accession 1914-004
  Date span is coverage
  Also known as the Godard Digest